Which one? Where is he?
哪一个?他在哪里?
Which one? That one?
哪一个?那个吗?
Oh, that one? The one bent over on the table?
他吗?趴在桌上的那个?
That's right. That young man.
没错 就是那个年轻人
Okay, that makes sense.
好的 知道了
He looks like the type.
他看起来就像是那种人
The man who lost to a pig.
会输给一头猪的人
I can't believe such a person exists!
我真不敢相信世上会有这种人
He has some nerve to say he wants to become a thegn.
他竟然还有种说 想成为臣子
So, all we have to do is tell him that he failed?
所以 我们只需要对他说 他没通过吗?
That's right, you just have to tell him.
没错 告诉他这个就行了
All right, that's fine with me.
好的 我没意见
Man,
天啊
I'm not sure if I can keep it at that, though.
但我可不能保证自己不笑场
Do you want to tease him?
你想捉弄他吗?
I mean, look at his dumb-looking face.
看看他那一副蠢样子
Go. I'll treat you to drinks later.
去吧 我等下请你喝酒
- Okay.
-好
You're laughing too much.
你笑得太大声了
- I can't help it! - You are too!
-我忍不住嘛 -你还不是一样
Speaking of dumb-looking faces, you guys
说到一副蠢样子 你们两个...
aren't that different.
也没什么两样
Olmar!
欧玛
Olmar! Excuse me.
欧玛 不好意思
My name is Brodd.
我叫布洛德
I am a member of the late king's corps.
我是已故国王的士兵
And?
所以呢?
And I came here to relay a message from Sir Wulf,
我是来替沃尔夫先生传话的
the captain of King Canute's thegns.
他是库奴特王的臣子首领
I know I failed.
我知道我失败了
Now, now...
这个嘛...
This is our job. Just let us deliver the message.
我们也只是来传话的
Olmar, about your request to join the king's thegns...
欧玛 关于你要求 成为国王的臣子一事
"Your will to offer your life to His Majesty
“你乐于为陛下牺牲性命的意愿
is splendid indeed," are the captain's words.
是我们迫切需要的” 这些是首领的原话
However, upon witnessing your skills, the captain has said
但是 在见识过你的才能之后 首领表示
that your swordsmanship has room for improvement.
你的剑术还有很大的改善空间
Therefore, I regret to inform you that...
因此 我很遗憾地通知你
I regret to inform you that...
我很遗憾地通知你...
There's nothing to regret! You lost to a pig!
根本没什么好遗憾的 因为你输给了一头猪
Stop it! Don't say that out loud!
不要这样啦 干嘛说得这么大声?
I can't breathe!
我呼吸困难
I heard you couldn't cut a pig?
我听说你连杀猪都不会?
Why is that?
怎么会这样?
Was the pig wearing a chain mail or something?
那头猪穿了链甲吗?
Actually, if it was a pig, was it wearing a swine mail?
其实 如果是猪的话 穿的该是猪链甲咯?
Pardon us. We shouldn't laugh at you.
请别见怪 我们实在不该嘲笑你
His job hunt isn't going well.
他的工作找得不太顺利
Why don't you guys refer him for a job?
你们何不给他介绍一份工作?
Oh, the chef at the palace was looking for a helper.
宫廷的主厨正在找帮手
He can't do it.
他办不到的啦
He can't even cut a pig!
他连杀猪都不行
As a warrior, I will make you pay for your humiliation with my sword.
竟敢侮辱我 身为战士 我会用我的剑让你付出代价
Take up your sword!
把你的剑拿出来
But you can't even cut a pig!
但你连杀猪都办不到
I'm going to die from laughing too much!
我真的会笑死
What the heck!
搞什么?
That wasn't nice, you weakling.
那样不对喔 你这个懦夫
- Come on, hurry! - Wait!
-快点 动作快 -等等
It's a fight!
有人在打架
They're by the stalls. It's five against one.
他们在摊子旁边 五打一
- They're using swords! - That means we get to see blood!
-他们手上拿着剑 -那我们就能看到血咯?
- Do it! - Kill him!
-快点! -杀了他!
You can do it, young 'un!
你可以的 年轻人
I'll fight him alone.
我跟他决斗就好
If we gang up on someone who can't even cut a pig,
如果我们联手对付 一个连杀猪都不会的人
it'll be a disgrace.
也太丢脸了
Don't lose.
别输咯
My, my, you're so serious.
我的天 你来真的
I'll help train you, Olmar.
我来帮你训练一下吧 欧玛
Come on, get up. Try harder.
快点 站起来 再努力一点
Jeez, he's as pathetic as they say he is.
天啊 他真的就跟大家说的一样可悲
Stand up, Olmar.
站起来 欧玛
Don't sleep during a duel.
别在决斗时睡着了
Brother...
哥哥
Brother, I was
哥哥 我被...
...humiliated.
羞辱了
I can tell just by looking.
看你的脸我就知道了
Hurry up and get up and kill that guy.
快点站起来 杀了那个人
Stand up.
站起来
Stand up, Olmar!
站起来 欧玛
He's so strong...
他好强壮
Brother... I...
哥哥 我...
Listen to me, Olmar.
听我说 欧玛
There are only two options left for a warrior who is humiliated.
被羞辱的战士只有两个选择
To kill or to die.
杀人或被杀
If you can't kill him, then die.
如果你杀不了他 你就去死吧
I will not allow you to go on with life and ignore
我不会让你装作没这回事
the fact that you were humiliated.
回头继续过日子
Fight and become a man.
学着抵抗 成为一个真正的男人
Today will be the day.
就在今天
- Brother... - Go on!
-哥哥... -快去
What's up with him?
他是怎么搞的?
Imagine it, Olmar.
欧玛 你想像一下...
Imagine yourself chopping off his head.
想像你自己砍下了他的头
Yes...
好
Project your voice from the bottom of your stomach.
气沉丹田 发出声音
- Yes! - More!
-好 -再大声
Yes!
好
Imagine your enemy writhing in his own blood and guts
想像一下你的敌人 在他自己的鲜血和内脏中挣扎
and crying tears of regret!
流下后悔的眼泪
Yes!
好
Get ready, Olmar!
准备好 欧玛
Kill that jerk! Kill him!
杀了那个混球 杀了他!
Yes!
好!
Go!
去吧!
After all that egging, he thinks he can do it.
被人怂恿了一番 他还真以为自己办得到
Your training is done.
你的训练结束了
You did it!
你办到了
Unbelievable!
真是不可思议
He can actually fight!
他真的会搏斗
This is getting exciting!
越来越令人兴奋了
Amazing!
太厉害了
- You were great! - Keep it up!
-你很强 -保持下去
Seriously?
真的假的?
- Come on! - That bastard!
-快点 -那个混球
Don't let him get away alive!
别让他活着离开
We have to clear our name right here, right now!
我们得立刻在这里挽回我们的名声
- Yeah!
-没错
Good job, Olmar.
干得好 欧玛
That's what I expect from my brother.
这才是我期望见到的弟弟
Now leave the rest to me.
剩下的就交给我吧
He died?
他死了?
I killed him?
我杀了他?
I killed... someone?
我杀了...人?
His eye...
他的眼睛...
It was punctured by a rock or something.
是被石头之类的东西砸到的
Olmar! Thorgil!
欧玛、托尔吉尔
Move! Get out of the way!
让开 别挡路
Wh... What's going on?!
这是怎么回事?
What happened?
发生了什么事?
You...
你...
What...
怎么...
Calm down, Dad.
爸 冷静
Calm down? You're telling me to calm down?
冷静?你叫我冷静?
You killed the king's messenger!
你杀了国王的传令兵
What are you going to do about this? This...
这下你该怎么办?这...
We are not in the wrong.
错的不是我们
What?
什么?
Olmar was humiliated and it led to a duel. He defended his honor.
欧玛被羞辱了 因而有了这场决斗 他捍卫了自己的尊严
But--
但是...
It was five against one.
是五打一
They can't complain that I joined in to help.
他们可不能抱怨我出手相助
If you're his parent, you should commend Olmar.
如果你真是欧玛的父母 你该称赞他
Duels are banned by the law.
法律禁止决斗
Nobody follows that law.
没有人遵守那条法律
If they're carrying around swords,
如果他们随身带着剑
they should know that humiliation comes with a price.
他们就该知道羞辱别人要付出代价
They knew that and still disparaged Olmar.
他们明知道这一点 仍然看不起欧玛
They're rude guys who deserve to die.
他们如此粗鲁无礼 死了活该
Out of the way! Make way!
滚开 让路!
What?
怎样?
They're guards!
是护卫
We are not wrong.
我们没有错
Duels like this happen all the time. Normally, we won't be punished.
这种决斗很常见 我们通常不会有事
Who is the one brazenly causing a commotion
是谁如此胆大包天 竟敢在陛下的领土上
in His Majesty's territory?
兴风作浪?
Give up and show yourselves.
快出来自首
What's going on? Olmar is still alive.
这是怎么回事?欧玛还活着
Even Ketil is here. Who is that other guy?
连凯特尔也在 另一个人又是谁?
I don't know. He's probably a family member.
我不知道 很可能是家人
I am King Canute's thegn, Thorgil, son of Ketil.
我是库奴特王的臣子托尔吉尔 凯特尔的儿子
My father Ketil and younger brother Olmar are here.
我父亲凯特尔和弟弟欧玛也在
It was an honest-to-goodness duel.
这是一场公平的决斗
We did nothing wrong.
我们没有做错事
Silence! Duels are banned by the king.
安静 国王下令禁止决斗
You bastards disrespected the king.
你们这群混球竟敢不尊重国王
You are under arrest.
你们被捕了
I knew it.
我就知道
I told you... I told you, Thorgil.
我告诉过你...托尔吉尔
Bring your hands back!
把手放在后面
Don't clench them!
别握那么紧
Wait a second! I am--
等等 我是...
Hand over your sword and put your hands behind your back.
把你的剑交出来 把手放在后面
Hey, did you not hear me?
喂 你没听到我说的话吗?
He did it...
他出手了
You bastard!
你这个混球
How... How dare you!
好大的胆子
Wh... Have you lost your mind, Thorgil?
这...你疯了吗 托尔吉尔?
We're done for! There's no turning back!
我们完蛋了 没有回头路了
I have something to ask you, you underling.
属下 我有话问你
I'm impatient.
我没有耐心
Be mindful of how you answer me.
小心回答我的问题
If you answer, I'll spare you.
如果你回答了 我就饶过你
Why did you make Olmar win?
你为什么让欧玛赢?
Huh?
什么?
"Make" me win?
“让”我赢?
Tell me.
快说
I... I didn't know--
我...我不知道
I warned you.
我警告你
Tell me.
快说
Why did you trick Olmar?
你为什么要设计陷害欧玛?
It was...
是为了...
to arrest Ketil.
逮捕凯特尔
In order to arrest Ketil
是为了以叛国罪
in the name of collective punishment for the treason
和他儿子对陛下大不敬的名义
and lese majesty committed by his son,
进行联合惩处 逮捕凯特尔
we made him kill the king's messenger.
我们才设计让他杀了信差
What have I ever done to deserve this?
我到底做错了什么 为何如此待我?
All I did was obey Sir Wulf's orders.
我纯粹只是听从沃尔夫先生的命令
Please let me get treatment.
请让我接受治疗
It's bleeding... It won't stop bleeding!
一直在流血...血流不止
It's all over... King Canute is targeting me.
一切都完了 库奴特王盯上我了
You're wrong, Dad.
你错了 爸
Thorgil...
托尔吉尔哥哥...
This is just the beginning.
这只是开始而已
We're up against a powerful enemy.
我们面对的是一个强大的敌人
I see...
我知道了...
Ketil and his family escaped, huh?
凯特尔和他的家人逃走了?
I apologize, Your Majesty.
对不起 陛下
We're staking out their ship and inn,
我们正在监视他们的船舰和旅店
but they haven't shown up.
但他们尚未现身
We're currently searching.
我们目前正在追查他们的下落
It is my responsibility for not being able
没有约束托尔吉尔
to restrain Thorgil.
是我的责任
He seems to be a very skilled warrior.
他似乎是一位非常厉害的战士
Yes, he was a good subordinate.
对 他是个优秀的部下
It doesn't affect our plan.
这不影响我们的计划
We still have an excuse to execute judgement.
我们仍然有执行判决的理由
We will head to Ketil's farm according to schedule.
我们仍然会按照计划 前往凯特尔的农场
If Ketil is not there, so be it.
如果凯特尔不在农场 也好
If he is there and resists, we just have to subdue them.
如果他在 而且还出手抵抗 我们只好制服他们
Yes, sir.
遵命
I will dispatch 32 thegns
我会指派32名随从
to be Your Majesty's bodyguards.
做陛下的保镖
Floki and his Jomsvikings would be an additional 70,
再加上弗洛基 和他的约姆战士共70人
so we will have an army of 102 soldiers.
我们总共会有102名士兵
That should be enough. When will Floki arrive?
这样应该够了 弗洛基何时抵达?
He'll arrive from Jomsborg within three days.
他从约姆斯伯格出发 三天内会抵达
Well then, in three days, we will depart at dawn.
好的 那么三天内 我们会在黎明时分出发
You may leave.
退下吧
Yes, sir.
遵命
What are you laughing at, King Sweyn?
斯韦恩王 你在笑什么?
Don't be so mad.
别生气了
There's nothing wrong with a father
一位父亲因为看到儿子
being happy to see his son growing up to be just like him.
越来越像他而感到开心 这有什么错呢?
Keep marching ahead.
继续前进
In order to reach the summit,
为了登顶
you will need more corpses.
你需要更多的尸体
All right.
好的
My guests, you can come out now.
客人 你们可以出来了
Man, this barrel reeks of salted food.
天啊 这个桶子都是咸食的味道
You are a lifesaver, Leif.
你救了我们一命 雷夫
We appreciate your kindness.
十分感谢你的好意
It's not out of kindness. This is a transaction.
这不是出于好意 这是一桩交易
Don't forget your side of the deal.
别忘了你们答应过我的事
- I wouldn't transport criminals like you. - It smells!
-我才不会运送你们这种罪犯 -好臭
Not out of kindness alone.
不只是因为好心
You don't know how hard it was to convince my people.
你不知道我花了多少心力 才能说服我同伴
Don't worry. A warrior never goes back on his word.
别担心 战士绝对说话算话
The Ketil Farm will purchase
凯特尔农场会以
all of your cargo at three times the standard price.
三倍的价格买下你所有的货
Don't forget about Thorfinn.
别忘了托尔芬
Of course! We will hand over that slave too.
当然不会 我们也会交上那位奴隶
Right, Dad?
对吧 爸?
Dad! You can come out--
爸 你可以出来了
Shut up!
闭嘴
Don't talk to me! Leave me alone!
别跟我说话 让我静一静
Someone's in a bad mood.
有人心情不好
Just don't forget about your promise.
别忘了你答应过的事
All right, let's call it a day.
好的 今天就到这里吧
Yeah, I agree.
好 我也这么觉得
Good work.
辛苦啦
What's the matter, Thorfinn?
怎么了吗 托尔芬?
Have you never seen a sunset before?
你从未见过夕阳吗?
It's not that...
不是...
Laugh at me all you want.
就尽管嘲笑我吧
Curse me all you want.
就尽管诅咒我吧
Everything is for the sake of a peaceful world.
这一切都是为了世界和平
of the love that was lost.
一切都是为了我们失去的爱
"Dark Clouds."
乌云
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒